

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

6-10, Seokye-ro 13-gil, Nowon-gu, Seoul, Rep. of KOREA

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.brain@kakaobrain.com | 🏕 blog.naver.com/sooftware | 🖸 sooftware | 🛅 hwan-kim

"Try your best rather than be the best"

Summary.

Current AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in electonic & communication engineering and minor in data science in university. My research interests include in technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis and natural language processing etc. I enjoy software development and sometimes I like to write my knowledge or thought. I wanna be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I've done and I'm doing.

Education

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

MAJOR B.E. IN ELECTRONIC & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING / MINOR B.E. IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021 (Expected)

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.70 / 4.5
- Courses: Capstone Design I-II, Al & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Computer Architecture, Operating System, C programming, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Circuit Theory I-II, Engineering Math I-II, Digital Logic, Phisics Electronic Technology, Object-Oriented Programming, Digital Signal Processing, System Programming, Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Data Communication, Data Structure & Algorithm, Computer Network, Network Programming, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Development Open-Source Software, Mobile Programming, Big Data Language, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Data Mining, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Statistical application, Planning Theory of IoT System

Career_

Kakao BrainPangyo, Gyunggi

Al Research Engineer Nov. 2020 - Present

- Research & Develop Speech and NLP fields
- Participation in NLP library development (Named Pororo)

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research & Develop English, Korean and Chinese Speech Recognition models
- Multilingual Text-To-Speech model development (10 languages)

Spoken Language Lab (Sogang Univ.)

Mapo, Seoul

Undergraduate Researcher

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Aug. 2018 - Present

- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models
- · Research Real-time Speech Recognition Based on Kaldi Toolkit

Technical Blog Naver Blog

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
 Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day
- Blog Link

Research Interests

Automatic Speech Recognition, Speech Synthesis, Natural Language Processing

Software Development, Software Architecture

Voice Activity Detection, Speech Enhancement, Cross-lingual

Publication

2020 End-to-End ASR Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

2020 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for E2E Korean Speech Recognition, arXiv pre-print

Project Experience

Multilingual Speech Synthesis

Kakao Brain

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

DIRECTOR

• Development of a speech synthesis model that supports 10 languages

• Supports for Voice-Cloning and Code-Switching

English, Korean and Chinese ASR Models Development

Kakao Brain

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

• Development of English, Korean and Chinese Wav2vec 2.0 Models

- Experiment for improving the speed of inference
- · Comparative experiment on accuracy / inference speed by output-unit such as Character, Grapheme and Subword

KoSpeechKwangwoon UniversityTEAM LEADERJan. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

- Recorded the performance of the model at 10.31 character error rate
- Got more than 100 stars on the GitHub site.
- GitHub / Technical Report

DIRECTOR

Extracurricular Activity

NLP Paper Reading

Kakao Brain

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Present

- · Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Discuss the content of the thesis and record it on this link

Deep Learning Principle Study Group

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - June. 2020

- GROUP MEMBER
- Joined a study group studying basics of deep learning with mathematics.
- Implemented nodes from scratch using numpy and pandas, read papers
- Study audio signal processing.

Speech Recognition Study Group

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

• Study speech signal processing (Spectrogram, Mel-Scale, MFCC etc ..)

• Review of the paper on speech recognition record it on this link

Skills

GROUP MEMBER

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Fairseq, PyTorch Lightning

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, NLTK

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

2020.11 **1st Place**, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival (President's Award)

2020.11 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival

2019.10 **12th Place**, Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 **People's Choice Award**, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Excellence Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

2020.01 School Representative, 5G-based ICT Convergence Service Idea Contest

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University